Guide to the James Deitrick Papers, 1900-1918
Department of Special Collections
James Deitrick Papers,
1900-1918
Special Collections M0140
Deitrick, James.
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Scope and Content
This material spans the period from 1900 - 1918 with the bulk from 1914 through 1917. There are also a number of undated items. The collection consists of letters, a Protocol, bills, extracts from a diary, copies of contracts, powers of attorney and other legal papers, misc. financial papers and notes, various lists, clips and printed material, brochures, telegrams and cables, form letters, postcards, memos, notes and drafts, sketches, autographs, calling cards and maps.
The subject matter pertains almost exclusively to business in Russia, China, Nicaragua, Mexico and the United States. This includes construction of railroads, development of mining and agricultural lands and resources, sale of farm equipment, and war material. A few items touch on political affairs, particularly the correspondence with Sun Yat-sen, H. C. Stuart, Herbert Hoover and the Nathan Hale volunteers. See also M 92 and the partial index following the container list.
Biographical Note
JAMES DEITRICK
1864 --born in [UNK]. Sterling, Kentucky; son of Philip K. and Aletha Elizabeth (Martin) D. --educated at the State University of Kentucky
1876 --railway telegraph operator
1880 --train dispatcher
1884 --railway superintendent
1892 --Southern Pacific Co. railway superintendent in California --Santa Fe, location engineer in construction dept. --confidential agent for Alan Manvel, Pres. of Santa Fe
1894 --agent for Brice and Morgan (or Brice Syndicate?)
1898 - 1904 --work in Mongolia
1899 --compiled and published Mongolian-English Dictionary
1908 --in fibre business
1909 --m. Violet Telkes of New York
1911 - 1916 --agent for Sun Yat-sen
1912 --president Central Railway and Navigation Co., a Central American concern with office in Paris
1913 --president European-American Finance and Development Co.
1914 --Consulting Engineers of Railroads and Mines --United States and Nicaragua Company --Compania de la Luz-Y-Los Angeles Mines
1914 - 1916 --legal agent for C. L. Best Gas Traction Co. and Lewis Motor Truck Co.
1915 --sales representative for Wellman, Peck and Co., wholesale grocers --agent for Colt's Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Co. in Russia, China and Japan --fiscal agent for Imperial Russian government --agent for The Russell and Company James Rees and Sons Company Fuel Savers Gas Stoves Mfg. Co. --president and director Chinese-American Plantation Co.
1916 --representative of Peters, White and Co. for importing potash.
1916 - 1917 --promotional work in Mexico and the United States
Deitrick was a capitalist, an engineer, location, construction and contractor of railways in America, China and Siberia. He was also president of the Chinese Construction Co. His death date is unknown although he is known to have been dead by fall, 1932.
Container List
- 1900-1913 (Folder 1)
  - 1. 1900,Photo of James Deitrick.
  - 2. 1902, Apr. 25.C. F. Dean to J. W. Harriman. Introduction to Deitrick, funds for China affairs., T.L.
  - 3. 1908, July 9.Wm. [Barbour] to J. Milne Barbour. Introduction to J.D., Belfast [Ireland] Rope Works., T.L.S.
  - 4. 1911, July 20.W. E. Chilton to Elliott Northcott., A.L.S. & cvr.
  - 5. 1912, Mar. 2.J. H. Goeke to J.D. Enclosing letter of introduction (now missing) to Myron T. Herrick, U. S. ambassador to France; Nicaragua affairs., T.L.S.
  - 6. 1912, Apr. 10.M. A. Karshner to Myron T. Herrick. Letter of introduction., T.L.S.
  - 7. 1912, Oct. 21.Typed copy of Protocol between Russia and Mongolia with ms. notations.
  - 8. 1912, Dec. 25.London Wall Estate Ltd. to J.D. Bill for office rent.
  - 9. 1912, Dec. 27.Same as #8.
  - 10. 1912-1915, Aug.James Deitrick. Extracts from Diary. Russian affairs., Holograph.
  - 11. 1913, Feb. 4.G[eorge] Simon to J.D. Nicaragua land, a signed option., T.L.S.
  - 12. 1913, Oct. 13.Pauling & Co., Ltd. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 13. 1913, Oct. 16.G. Simon to J.D. Nicaragua land., T.L.S.
  - 14. 1913, Oct. 16.Baron Antonin de Mandat-Grancey to George Simon. Nicaragua Timber and Fruit Lands Co., T.L. (copy)
  - 15. 1913, Oct. 17.George Simon to J.D. Nicaragua interests., T.L.S.
  - 16. 1913, Oct. 20.[James Deitrick] to George Simon., T.L.
  - 17. 1913, Oct. 20.[James Deitrick] to Nicaragua Timber and Fruit Lands Co., Board of Directors., T.L.
  - 18. 1913, Oct. 28.in French. J[ean] Boisse to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 19. 1913, Oct. 29.in French. J[ean] Boisse to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 20. 1913, Oct. 29.J. Boisse to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 21. 1913, Nov. 6.[J.D.] to Jean Boisse with signed copy of contract., T.L.
  - 22. 1913, Dec. 9.Georges Fleureau to J.D. re: Bara & Mathieu., T.L.S. & copy.
- 1914 (Folder 2)
  - 1. Jan. 12.Bliss, Ballett & Co. to J.D. Steamship reservations., T.L.S.
  - 2. Jan. 12.James A. O'Gorman to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 3. Jan. 15.F. [Alcántara] to J.D. Caracas business., T.L.S.
  - 4. Feb. 4.Thomas J. Walsh to Charles S. Hartman. Introducing J.D., Ecuador., T.L.S. & cvr.
  - 5. Mar. 7.Power of attorney. J.D. to Henry A. Wolff., T.D.S.
  - 6. Mar. 16.William V. Alford to J.D. China, Alaska and South America interests., T.L.S.
  - 7. Mar. 17.W. B. Storey to J.D. Railroads., T.L.S.
  - 8. Mar. 18.G. F. Sulzberger to J.D. Nicaragua lands., T.L.S.
  - 9. Mar. 25.Chicago National Bank of the Republic to J.D., T.L.S. & advise of credit.
  - 10. Mar. 27.Confirmation slip of #9.
  - 11. Mar. 31.Netherlands Farms Co. of Calif., Typed Balance Sheet.
  - 12. [Mar. 31].Netherlands Farms Co., Typed List of Stockholders.
  - 13. May 13.E. R. Lilienthal to J.D. Netherlands Farms Co., T.L.S.
  - 14. May 16.(Illegible) to J.D. Bananas., T.pc.S.
  - 15. Sept. 7.[J.D.] to Samuel Hill. Redwood railroad ties, Calif. coast railroad route., T.L.
  - 16. Sept. 11.Henry Clifford Stuart to David Lloyd George. Anti-British, anti-gold standard., T.L.S.
  - 17. 1914, Sept. 12.[J.D.] to [Herbert C.] Hoover. Netherlands Farms Co. property, Natomas, farm lands for immigrants, anti-Johnson sentiments (suggests Hoover as his opponent for Senate)., T.L.
  - 18. Sept. [12?].[J.D.] to H. C. Hoover. Natomas, J.D.'s business, railroad ties & routes in Calif. Albion River area., T.L.
  - 19. Oct. 20.Henry Clifford Stuart to Robert M. LaFollette. National political & diplomatic morals (or lack of)., T.L.S.
  - 20. Oct. 28.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D. Personal description, finance, Dr. [Sun Yat-sen], Richard W. Austin, Mrs. Stuart's German education, white man's governments, China., T.L.S.
  - 21. [Oct. 28].Printed record of H. C. Stuart with typed and holograph additions., Enclosure of above.
  - 22. [Oct. 28].Congressional Record. Clip of Sept. 13 with letters of H. C. Stuart. (1913), Enclosure.
  - 23. [Oct. 28].Congressional Record. Extract Mar. 30, 1914. H. C. Stuart., Enclosure.
  - 24. Oct. 28.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 25. Oct. 28.Jno. F. Stevens to J.D. Calif. timber tract and railroad ties., A.L.S.
  - 26. Oct. 28.Bela Telkes de Kelenfold to J.D. Nicaragua climate, plant growth, seeds., A.L.S.
  - 27. Oct. 30.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D. Photos for the Doctor [Sun Yat-sen], Yuan Shi-kai, China., T.L.S.
  - 28. Oct. 31.Clip re: Wm. Averill Harriman.
  - 29. Oct.The Bull Tractor., Prospectus.
  - 30. Nov. 1.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D. Japan & China., T.L.S.
  - 31. Nov. 5.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D. Sun Yat-sen, photos & brief (enclosed), war., T.L.S.
  - 32. Nov. 5.Henry Clifford Stuart. Brief for photo., T.L.S.
  - 33. Nov. 10.[J.D.] to Edward Remus. Bringing farmers to Alaska, tractors, export dried fruits, Telkes girls., T.L.
  - 34. 1914, Nov. 10.G. Frederick Wright to J.D. Books to be presented in Russia, William Stevenson, Alaskan R.R., printed brochure of one book., T.L.S.
  - 35. Nov. 18.[J.D.] to John F. Stevens. Albion, Calif. timber tract, proposed rail line., T.L.
  - 36. Nov. 21.John Downey Works to George T. Marye, Jr. Introducing J.D. to U. S. ambassador to Russia., T.L.(copy)
  - 37. Nov. 30.Sun Yat-sen to J.D. Needs money, copy of letter to Woodrow Wilson, Chinese Huerta, revolt against Yuan Shi-kai, copy of letter to Morgan Co., Young China., A.L.S. & cvr.
  - 38. Dec. 8.C. L. Best Gas Traction Company. to J.D. Specifications of Wagons., T.L.S.
  - 39. Dec. 14.Bull Tractor Company to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 40. Dec. 15.Illegible to J.D. Trying to get Telkes girls out of concentration camp., A.L.S. in French.
    & typed translation
  - 41. Dec. 24.[Lt. Tector?] to J.D. Telkes girls in concentration camp., A.L.S.
  - 42. Dec. 30.G. Frederick Wright to J.D. Senator Lin, China, Russia., T.L.S.
  - 43. Dec. 31John W. McGrath (sec. to T.R.) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 44. 1914.Printed pamphlet in Russian.
  - 45. [1914].Natomas Consolidated of California., Blank lease form.
  - 46. [1914?]. What is Natomas Consolidated of California., Typed brochure.
- 1915, January (Folder 3)
  - 1. Jan. 1.[Sun Yat-sen] to J.D., Tel. or cable.
  - 2. Jan. 4.Newcomb Carlton's sec. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 3. Jan. 5.John Burke to J.D. Farm machinery, Larimore & Webb, J.S. Murphy, farm superintendents for Russian wheat land, Cooper., T.L.S.
  - 4. Jan. 6,C. L. Best Gas Traction Co. to J.D. Apptmt as legal agent abroad for Best & Lewis Motor Truck Co., T.L.S.
  - 5. Jan. 7.George E. Chamberlain to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 6. 1915, Jan. 7.San Francisco Chamber of Commerce Activities., Clips.
  - 7. Jan. 7.Asle J. Gronna to Geo. E. Chamberlain List of large scale farmers in N. Dakota. Autograph note on verso., T.L.
  - 8. Jan. 8.J.D. to [UNK], A.L. (draft of form letter)
  - 9. Jan. 8.J.D. to [UNK], T.L.S. (form letter)
  - 10. Jan. 8.[J.D.] to John Burke, T.L.
  - 11. Jan. 8.[J.D.] to George T. Webb, T.L.
  - 12. Jan. 8.R. W. Farrar (sec. to Sen. McCumber) to J.D. List of large farmers in N. Dakota., T.L.S.
  - 13. Jan. 8.George T. Webb to J.D., Tel.
  - 14. Jan. 8.George T. Webb to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 15. Jan. 11.J. D. Bacon to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 16. Jan. 11.George T. Webb to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 17. Jan. 12.J. S. Murphy to J.D. Farming advice, interest in superintendant job., T.L.S.
  - 18. Jan. 14.O. J. Sorlie to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 19. Jan. 14.Jacques L. Vauclain to J.D., T.L.
  - 20. Jan. 14.George T. Webb to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 21. Jan. 16.J. P. Beltz to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 22. Jan. 17.[J.D.] to Thomas P. Cooper, T.L.
  - 23. Jan. 17.[J.D.] Carl Gaumitz & W. R. Porter. Offering positions., T.L.
  - 24. Jan. 17.[J.D.] to J. S. Murphy., T.L.
  - 25. Jan. 17.[J.D.] George T. Webb, T.L.
  - 26. Jan. 19.J. S. Murphy to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 27. Jan. 20.U. L. Burdick to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 28. Jan. 21.[Carl Gaumnitz] to J.D., T.L. (frag.)
  - 29. Jan. 21.A. T. Jackson to J.D. Supplying machinery., T.L.S.
  - 30. Jan. 21.G. J. Johnson to George S. Houston., T.L.S.
  - 31. 1915, Jan. 21.Hotel Theresa, N.Y.C. to J.D., Bill.
  - 32. Jan. 22.George T. Webb to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 33. Jan. 22.W.R. Porter to J.D., T.L.S. (frag.)
  - 34. Jan. 23.[J.D.] to Bernard M. Baruch., T.L.
  - 35. Jan. 23.[J.D.] to Mark A. Carleton., T.L.
  - 36. Jan. 23.[J.D.] to George E. Chamberlain., T.L.
  - 37. Jan. 23.[J.D.] to J. Henry Goeke., T.L.
  - 38. Jan. 23.[J.D.] to A. T. Jackson., T.L.
  - 39. Jan. 23.[J.D.] to A. Scherbatsky., T.L.
  - 40. Jan. 25.[J.D.] to J. C. Barclay., T.L.
  - 41. Jan. 25.[J.D.] to P. J. Beltz., T.L.
  - 42. Jan. 25.[J.D.] to Carl Gaumnitz., T.L.
  - 43. Jan. 25.[J.D.] to J. S. Murphy., T.L.
  - 44. Jan. 25.[J.D.] to W. R. Porter., T.L.
  - 45. Jan. 25.[J.D.] to George T. Webb., T.L.
  - 46. Jan. 25.Frank Oliver to J. D., T.L.S.
  - 47. Jan. 26.Mark A. Carleton to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 48. Jan. 26.[J.D.] to M. Duboss., T.L.
  - 49. Jan. 26.[J.D.] to A. D. Wilson., T.L.
  - 50. Jan. 26.Emerson-Brantingham Implement Co. to J. D., T.L.S.
  - 51. Jan. 26.Emerson-Brantingham to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 52. Jan. 26.Emerson-Brantingham to James Rees & Sons., T.L.S.
  - 53. Jan. 26.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 54. Jan. 27.Burrell Engineering & Construction Co. to J.D. Grain elevator plans., T.L.S.
  - 55. Jan. 27.Sherwin-Williams Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 56. Jan. 27.[Sun Yat-sen] to [J.D.], Cable.
  - 57. Jan. 27.George T. Webb to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 58. 1915, Jan. 27.Donald Wright to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 59. Jan. 28.J. H[enry] Goeke to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 60. Jan. 29.[J.D.] to Emerson-Brantingham., T.L.
  - 61. Jan. 29.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 62. Jan. 29. Stuttgarter Sanitary Woolen Underwear Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 63. Jan. 30.[J.D.] to W. G. Marfield., T.L.
  - 64. Jan. 30.[J.D.] to Donald Wright., T.L.
- 1915, February - March (Folder 4)
  - 1. Feb. 5.Sun Yat-sen to J.D. Future plans, failure of second revolution., A.L.S.
  - 2. Mar. 15.[J.D.] to Alexis Sergius Ermoloff., T.L.
  - 3. Mar. 15.E. D. Winslow to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 4. Mar. 16.A[lexis Sergius] Ermolof to J.D., A.N.S.
  - 5. [1915], Mar. 16.G. Kozakow to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 6. Mar. 18.[J.D.] to Count Musin-Puskin., T.L.
  - 7. Mar. 19.[J.D.] to Liang Tun-yen. China., T.L.
  - 8. Mar. 19.[J.D.] to Paul Samuel Reinsch., T.L.
  - 9. Mar. 19.[J.D.] to Unknown and copy. Relations with Russia, Alaska Railroad, extension of Trans-Siberian Railway., T.L.
  - 10. Mar. 21.[J.D.] to G. Kozakow., T.L.
  - 11. Mar. 23.J.D. to Serge D. Sozonov and copy., T.L.S.
  - 12. Mar. 23.J.D. to Serge D. Sozonov and copy., T.L.S.
  - 13. Mar. 26.[J.D.] to Alexander Krivocheine., T.L.
  - 14. [1915], Mar. 26,[J.D.] to Alexander Krivocheine. Turkestan., T.L.
  - 15. Mar. 26.[J.D.] to C. B. Rookhloff. Railroad and agricultural equipment manufacture., T.L.
  - 16. Mar. 26.[J.D.] to Grand Duke Alexander., T.L.
  - 17. 1915, Mar. 27.[J.D.] to C. B. Rookhloff & copy., T. L.
  - 18. Mar. 27.[J.D.] to Sun Yat-sen. Mongolia, Gen. Hwang., T.L.
- 1915, April - May (Folder 5)
  - 1. Apr. 2.[J.D.] to S. D. Sazonov., T.L.
  - 2. Apr. 6.C. N. Beal to J.D., T.L.
  - 3. Apr. 11.Charles S. Wilson to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 4. Apr. 16.Bill of lading and list to J.D.
  - 5. Apr. 19.Wellman, Peck & Co. to J.D. Forwarding trunk of samples.
  - 6. Apr. 27.Agreement in Russian with seal and translation James Deitrick, Eugene E. Skorniakoff & Joseph Polkhovski.
  - 7. Apr.Wellman, Peck & Co., Printed brochure.
  - 8. May 4.[J.D.] to Joseph Polkhovski., T.L.
  - 9. May 4.[J.D.?] to Michael E. Skorniakoff., T.L. (frag.)
  - 10. May 5.Wellman, Peck & Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 11. May 6.Colt's Patent Fire Arms Mfg. Co. to J.D. Requests J.D. to act as sales rep. in China and Japan., T.L.S.
  - 12. May 6.[J.D.] to Emperor of Russia with proposals regarding railroads., T.L.
  - 13. May 6.Emerson-Brangingham to J.D. & copy., T.L.S.
  - 14. May 12.[J.D.] to C. L. Best., T.L.
  - 15. May 12.[J.D.] to C. L. Best Gas Traction Co., T.L.
  - 16. May 12.[J.D.] to D. Telkes., T.L.
  - 17. May 12.Robert Dollar Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 18. May 12.Allen Merril Rogers to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 19. May 13.Wellman, Peck & Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 20. May 18.K. I. Kreslinga. Chemical and Bacteriological Report, Printed pamphlet.
  - 21. May 20.C. N. Beal to J.D. Russia, Panama-Pacific Exposition, sinking of Lusitania., T.L.S.
  - 22. 1915, May 20.F. C. Drew to J.D. Calif. timber., T.L.S.
  - 23. [May 23].Joseph Polkhovski to J.D. in French., A.L.S.
  - 24. May 23.Joseph Polkhovski to J.D., A. Postcard S.
  - 25. [May 27].Hotel Astoria, Petrograd, Russia to J.D., Bill.
  - 26. [May 29].Printed pamphlet in Russian.
  - 27. [May 31].Hotel Astoria, Petrograd to J.D., Bill.
- 1915, June (Folder 6)
  - 1. June 5.[C. L. Best Gas Traction Co.] to Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd., T.L. A copy.
  - 2. June 5.[C. L. Best Co.?] to Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd. Authorization to act as agent for Lewis Motor Truck Co., T.L. A copy.
  - 3. June 5.[Lewis Motor Truck Co.?] to Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd., T.L.
  - 4. [June 5].Phone message. General Ropp to J.D.
  - 5. June 7.Colt's Patent Fire Arms Mfg. Co. to J.D., T.L.S. & cvr.
  - 6-8. June 8.3 same date. [J.D.] to Sergius D. Sazonov. Safe conduct, pistol, Hungarian prisoner of war (Telkes)., T.L.
  - 9. June 9.Colt's Pat. Fire Arms Mfg. Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 10. June 11.Hotel Astoria, Petrograd to J.D., Bill.
  - 11. June 12.[Geo. Jarovenn?] to J.D. A Prescription for Saccharin., A.L.S.
  - 12. June 13.[J.D.] to M. Barc., T.L.
  - 13. [June 16?].Notes on plans in Russia [J.D.?].
  - 14. June 18.Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd. to J.D., T.L.
  - 15. June 22.[J.D.] to C. N. Beal. Proposed American bank in Russia., T.L.
  - 16. June 22.[J.D.] to C. L. Best., T.L.
  - 17. June 22.[J.D.] to C. L. Best Gas Traction Co., T.L.
  - 18. 1915, June 22.[J.D.] to C. L. Best Gas Traction Co., T.L.
  - 19. June 22.[J.D.] to Lewis Motor Truck Co., T.L.
  - 20. June 22.[J.D.] to Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd., T.L.
  - 21. June 22.[J.D.?] to Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd., T.L.
  - 22. June 22.[J.D.] to Russian Land Reclamation Co. Ltd., T.L.
  - 23. June 22.[J.D.] to W. B. Wellman., T.L.
  - 24. June 24.[J.D.?] to L. F. Grauman., T.L. (frag.)
  - 25. June 29.[J.D.] to George T. Marye. Ernest Telkes de Kelenfold, war prisoner., T.L.
  - 26. [1915?], June 30.Notes, financial.
  - 27-29. June.Hotel Astoria, Petrograd to J.D., 3 bills.
- 1915, July (Folder 7)
  - 1-4. Jul. 1.[J.D.] to Minister of the Navy (Russia) Sale of ships and armaments, submarines, gasoline., 4 T.L.
  - 5. Jul. 1.[J.D.] to Minister of War (Russia). Guns and ammunition., T.L.
  - 6. Jul. 5.[J.D.] to Minister of the Navy. Siberian railroad., T.L.
  - 7. Jul. 5.[J.D.] to Minister of War., T.L.
  - 8. Jul. 12.J.D. to [Minister of the Navy?]., Typed confidential memo.
  - 9. Jul. 12.Hotel Astoria, Petrograd to J.D., Bill.
  - 10. Jul. 16.in French. [UNK] to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 11. Jul. 17.[J.D.] to P. L. Bark., T.L.
  - 12. Jul. 17.[J.D.] to Baron E. Ropp., T.L.
  - 13-14. Jul. 19.[J.D.] to Baron E. Ropp., 2 T.L.
  - 15-16. Jul. 19.[J.D.] to Adolphus Stanislavitch Roshkovsky. Apptmt. as sales agent for C. L. Best., 2 T.L.
  - 17. Jul. 20.C. L. Best Gas Traction Co. & G. T. Marye to [Whom It May Concern]. J. D. is legal agent., T.L.
  - 18-19. 1915, Jul. 20.[J.D.] to General Polivanoff. Gasoline, horses., 2 T.L.
  - 20. Jul. 22.[J.D.] to Gen. Polivanoff., T. L.
  - 21. Jul. 23.George Thomas Marye to J.D., T. L.
  - 22. Jul. 24.[J.D.?] to Baron E. Ropp. The Russell & Co. traction engines., T. L.
  - 23-24. Jul. 27.J.D. to Baron E. Ropp., T.L. in Russian & A.Df.
  - 25. Jul. 27.[J.D.] to War Dept., Russia. The Russell & Co., T.L.
  - 26-27. Jul. 29.[J.D.] to Gen. Byelayev., T.L. (English & Russian)
  - 28. Jul. 29.in Russian of above., A.Df.
  - 29. Jul. 29.George Thomas Marye to Minister of Foreign Affrs., T.L.
  - 30. July.Hotel Astoria, Petrograd to J.D., Bill.
- 1915, August - December (Folder 8)
  - 1. Aug. 4.[J.D.] to Liang Tun-yen. East Turkestan., T.L.
  - 2. Aug. 16.George Thomas Marye to J.D., A.L.S. & cvr.
  - 3. Aug. 18.The Russell & Co. to J.D., T.L.S. & list.
  - 4. Aug. 31.Vienna to American Embassy, Petrograd. Note Verbale re: Telkes., T.D.
  - 5. Sept. 10.J[oseph] P. Tumulty to J.D., T.L.S. & cvr.
  - 6. Sept. 13.Irmgard Ecker to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 7. Sept. 23.J. C. White to J.D. Lt. Telkes., T.L.S.
  - 8. Oct. 2.G. Kehlenbring, Jr. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 9. Oct. 13.W. Morgan Shuster to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 10. Oct. 29.J. P. Morgan & Co. Export Dept. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 11-12. Oct. 2.The Russell & Co. to J.D., 2 T.L.S.
  - 13. Nov. 3.C. Q. Hildebrant. Charles W. Kirk, clerk of courts (Ohio)., Typed certificate.
  - 14-15. Nov. 5.J.D. to Z. Januszewski., A.L.S. & A.N.S.
  - 16. 1915, Nov. 5.Z. Januszewski to J.D., A.L.S. in German
  - 17. Nov. 8.Power of Atty. The Russell & Co. to J.D., T.D. & 2 copies or versions.
  - 18. Nov. 10.C. O. Townsend to J.D. Sugar beet seeds., T.L.S.
  - 19. Nov. 12.Belaeiff to J.D., Tel.
  - 20. Nov. 15.Gorovskovski to J.D., Tel.
  - 21. Nov. 22.Co O. Townsend to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 22. Nov. 23.George E. Chamberlain to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 23. Nov. 24.[J.D.] to Continental Sugar Co., T.L.
  - 24. Nov. 26.Continental Sugar Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 25. Nov. 26.Michigan Sugar Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 26. Nov. 27.C. O. Townsend to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 27. Nov. 30.Anaheim Sugar Co. (Arthur R. Peck) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 28. Dec. 3.C. O. Townsend to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 29. Dec. 6.Spreckels Sugar Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 30. Dec. 6.C. O. Townsend to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 31. Dec. 9.Wisconsin Sugar Co. (J. S. Lawson) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 32. Dec. 9.Chinese-American Plantation Co. Minutes of Directors' Meeting. China., T.D. & copy.
  - 33. Dec. 17.Iowa Sugar Co. (Earl C. Moore) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 34. Dec. 28.C. O. Townsend to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 35. Dec. 29.[J.D.] to Charles Adams Holder. Passport request., T.L.
  - 36-38. Dec. 31.The Russell & Co. to J.D., 2 T.L.S. & 1 list.
  - 39. Dec.Bond Agreement copy. Great Western Sugar Co., T.D.
  - 40. 1915.Agreement blank. Russian & English. Russia and J.D., T.D.
  - 41. [1915].Joseph Polkhovski to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 42. 1915.The Russell Gas Tractor., Printed brochure.
- 1916, January - December (Folder 9)
  - 1. Jan. 1.The Russell & Co. to Sec. of State, T.L.
  - 2. Jan. 3.The Fuel Saver Stove Co. to Sec. of State., T.L.
  - 3. Jan. 3.James Rees & Sons Co. to Sec. of State., T.L.
  - 4. Jan. 4.Peters, White & Co. (Frederick W. White) to J.D. Potash., T.L.S.
  - 5. Jan. 5.Bethlehem Steel Corp. (J. H. Ward) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 6. Jan. 8.William A. Ashlbrook to Sec. of State., T.L.
  - 7. Jan. 8.Roscoe C. McCulloch to Sec. of State, Robert Lansing., T.L.
  - 8. Jan. 9.Dunham, Carrigan & Hayden Co. to Chinese-American Plantation Co., Bill.
  - 9. Jan. 11.Frederick W. White to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 10. Jan. 12.J.D. to C. Renwick Smedberg. Potash., T.L.S.
  - 11. Jan. 15.The Fuel Saver Stove Co. (C. A. Notman) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 12. Jan. 15.C. O. Townsend to J.D. Sugar beet seeds., T.L.S.
  - 13. Jan. 19.The Russell & Co. (E. C. Merwin) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 14. Jan. 19.Charles B. Welsh to J.D. Denial of passport, T.L.S.
  - 15. Jan. 21.[UNK] Hvoslef to A/S Wallendahl & Son., T.L.S.
  - 16. Jan. 31.E. W. Moir to J.D. Potash., T.L.
  - 17. Feb. 3.The Russell & Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 18. Feb. 5.D. A. Rees to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 19. Feb. 7.George G. Allen to J.D. N.Y. real estate., T.L.S.
  - 20. Feb. 9.H. E. Cole (Standard Oil of New York) to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 21. 1916, Feb. 9.Russell H. Scott to [J.D.], A.L.S.
  - 22. [Mar. 4].Ernest Telkes to J.D., A.pc. S.
  - 23. Mar. 5.C. Renwick Smedberg to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 24. Mar. 6.C. L. Best Gas Traction Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 25. Mar. 7.John J. Spurgeon to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 26. Mar. 22.C. Renwick Smedberg to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 27. Mar. 23.J. W. Floyd to J.D. Swift & Co. & Armour., T.L.S.
  - 28. Mar. 27.Henry Clifford Stuart to J.D., T.N.S.
  - 29. Mar. 29.John F. Pogue to J.D. Tablet of Daniel Boone., T.L.S.
  - 30. Apr. 17.Colt's Pat. Fire Arms Mfg. Co. to J.D. Chinese market., T.L.S.
  - 31. Apr. 20.[W. C.?] Ralston to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 32. Apr. 21.Marvin Hughitt to J.D. Siberian mastodon., T.L.S.
  - 33. Apr. 27.Colt's Pat. Fire Arms Mfg. Co. to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 34. Apr. 27.[J.D.] to Zach T. Davis. Packing plant for China., T.L.
  - 35. May 1.J. Hampton Rich (Boone Trail Highway Assn.) to J.D. Boone tablet., T.L.S.
  - 36. May 9.Robert Lansing to James A. O'Gorman. Telkes., T.L.S.
  - 37. May 10.[Alfred De Ropp] to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 38. May 20.C. N. Beal to Dear Sir. Chinese affairs, the Venture Co., T.L.S.
  - 39. June 28.[E. Remie] to J.D., T.L.S.
  - 40. June 30.Dunham, Carrigan & Hayden Co. to Chinese-American Plantation Co., Bill.
  - 41. Jul. 5.J.D. to Lin Sun. Guns., Sales slip holograph.
  - 42. Jul. 6.Chinese Nationalist League of America to J.D., A.L.S.
  - 43-45. 1916, Jul. 9.Glenn L. Martin Co. to J.D. Airplanes., 2 T.L.S., 1 T.L.
  - 46. Jul. 19.Dunham, Carrigan & Hayden Co. to J.D., Bill.